# MILAN BAROT

bmilan.6979@gmail.com ❖ (917) 497-6979 ❖ Frisco, TX

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Engineer experienced in working across different stages of data pipeline, including acquisition, integration, ODS and real-time data marts. Adept in working quickly and efficiently in close collaboration with analytic, engineering, and other stake holders

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

CBRE, Dallas, TX,

May 2021 – current

Data Engineer

- Created and maintained optimal data pipeline architecture.
- Assembled large, complex data sets that meet functional / non-functional business requirements.
- Identified, designed, and implemented internal process improvements: automating manual processes, optimizing data delivery, re-designing infrastructure for greater scalability, etc.
- Built the infrastructure required for optimal extraction, transformation, and loading of data from a wide variety of data sources using SQL and cloud database technologies.
- Used GO as programming Language, Snowflake as the database storage, Mesos to manage the Azure cloud infrastructure, Jenkins for Continuous integration and deployment.
- Worked with stakeholders including the Executive, Product, Data and Design teams to assist with data-related technical issues and supported their data infrastructure needs.
- Kept our data separated and secure across national boundaries through multiple data centers and regions.
- Worked with data and analytics experts to strive for greater functionality in our data systems.
- Developed best practices for database design and development activities.
- Ability to quickly analyze existing SQL code and make improvements to enhance performance, taking advantage of new SQL features, close security gaps, and increase robustness and maintainability of the code.
- Took on technical leadership responsibilities of database projects across various scrum teams
- Managed exploratory data analysis to support database and dashboard development

# Mollissoft Inc., El Segundo, CA

Mar 2020 – current

SOL Developer

- Assemble large, complex data sets that meet functional / non-functional business requirements.
- Analyzing and organizing raw data
- Identifying, designing, and implementing internal process improvements: automating manual processes, optimizing data delivery, re-designing infrastructure for greater scalability, etc.

#### AmNet Services, Fairfield, NJ

Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

Radio Frequency Field Engineer

- Working directly with senior RF engineer to monitor and record cell site signal strength.
- Made 911 calls to ensure all information is reaching the correct E911 call center.
- Drive testing of sites following the re-home of E911 circuits.
- Performed site surveys and in-depth walkthroughs.
- Assisted senior RF engineer in cell site troubleshooting. (Dropped calls, poor coverage, and overloaded circuits).
- Indulged in E911 Sprint project and Massive MIMO Nokia project.

# Borough of Manhattan Community College, CUNY, New York

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

College Assistant

• Duties included scanning, photocopying, responding, updating and maintaining handbooks and materials for distribution. Operating computers, computer software and other electronic equipment in performing the assigned tasks. Providing assistance to students and administrative staff.

#### **EDUCATION**

# CITY UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK, New York, NY

Dec 2018

Associates in Applied Science in Computer Information Systems

Coursework: Web Programming, Database Management Systems, Telecommunication Networks, Multimedia Programming, UNIX, Discrete Structures, Object Oriented Programming with Java

## WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY, Vienna, VA

Mar 2022

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology in Software Engineering

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Data:

MS SQL Server 2016/2019 Visual Studio 2016/2016

Microsoft Visio

SSIS, SSRS, SSAS

Data Pipeline & Workflow Management

Data Architecture/Data Assembling

**ETL Pipelines** 

Data Infrastructure Development

**Technical Documentation** 

**Programming Languages:** 

SQL/T-SQL, PostgreSQL, Python/GO,

JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Cloud:

AWS, Azure